crystalgraphics.com 2014-12-02

# CrystalGraphics - Energize your presentations, Videos and Web sites!

CrystalGraphics Privacy Policy

Welcome to CrystalGraphics' Internet website! We are proud to have this opportunity to tell you a little about our products and our company. We are confident you like what you see. But before you begin exploring, we'd like to review the steps we have taken to ensure that on-line visitors of all ages have a safe, enjoyable experience.

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

Your privacy is important to us. At CrystalGraphics, we value our customers’ privacy and have made it our policy to provide on-line content that requires minimal collection of information from our visitors. Furthermore, to better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our on-line information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we intend to make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. Any significant changes to this Privacy Policy shall be printed in blue italics for a period of 30 days.

**How We Collect Information**

Below are some of the ways in which a visitor may provide information to us on-line and how we may use that information.

**Domain Name Recognition**

Our web servers automatically recognizes a visitor's domain name, however, they do not recognize a visitor's e-mail.

**Use of Cookies**

Cookies are small bits of information that a website transfers to an individual's computer for record keeping purposes. We use cookies in a variety of ways to create a more personalized on-line experience for the user. These cookies contain no personal information about you and no one but CrystalGraphics can retrieve the cookies. These cookies are stored within your browser. Information which may be obtained through cookies is not sold, rented or provided to third parties and is not used internally by CrystalGraphics for any purpose other than to learn in the aggregate which websites may have referred our website visitors, as well as to enhance your experience on our website.

**Information Actively Provided by Our Visitors**

We do not require visitors to register or provide any information before entering our websites. However, there are several places where visitors may choose to provide personally identifiable information about themselves. CrystalGraphics treats this information as strictly confidential. Unless we tell you otherwise, CrystalGraphics uses the information only for the purpose it was provided and will not give, lease, trade, share or sell this personal information to another entity or person outside of CrystalGraphics. 

**For example:**

  * **E-Newsletters:** Some of our pages permit you to register to receive e-mail newsletters and/or product or promotional update emails in the future by providing your name and e-mail address. We will not give, lease, trade, share or sell these names or email addresses to another entity or person outside of CrystalGraphics. Any e-mail you receive from CrystalGraphics will allow you to "unsubscribe" from this informational service at any time. 
  * **Free or Trial Product Downloads:** Some of our pages permit you to download free or trial software after providing your name and e-mail address. Generally, just below those name and email fields, you are also provided with an option to receive e-mail newsletters and/or product or promotional update emails in the future. We will not give, lease, trade, share or sell these names or email addresses to another entity or person outside of CrystalGraphics. Any e-mail you receive from CrystalGraphics will allow you to unsubscribe from this informational service at any time.
  * **Purchase Pages** : You may also buy products on our website, in which case you will be asked for your name, address and credit card or other payment information. This information will be treated by CrystalGraphics as strictly confidential and is used by CrystalGraphics only for the purpose of verifying and collecting the payment and shipping the order to you at the address specified. It is never provided in any form to any person outside CrystalGraphics or to any other company, except that your name and address are provided to our shipping company and, in some cases, to the government for tax purposes, if required by law. Any follow-up or product or promotional e-mail you receive from CrystalGraphics after your purchase will allow you to unsubscribe from this informational service at any time.
  * **Questions** : On some pages our visitors can submit comments or ask questions. The only personally identifiable information that we collect is the sender’s name and e-mail address. We will not give, lease, trade, share or sell these names or email addresses to another entity or person outside of CrystalGraphics. We do not save any personally identifiable information associated with comments, and we only save e-mail addresses associated with questions in order to respond to those questions.
  * **Sweepstakes** : We occasionally offer sweepstakes on our pages. We collect the name and email addresses of the people entering the sweepstakes. Rarely, this information may be shared with the company providing the sweepstakes prizes, but if so, this fact will be clearly stated in the online entry form. Otherwise, we will not give, lease, trade, share or sell these names or email addresses to another entity or person outside of CrystalGraphics. Of course, we also collect the information necessary for prize fulfillment from those who win. If a prize is valued at over $600, a social security number will be requested. The first initial, last name, hometown and state of all winners will be included on a Winners List. The Winners List will be provided upon request and as required by law. Information required for tax purposes, email addresses, the Winner’s List or other information required by law is kept as required by law. All other information is deleted within 60 days of the final selection of the sweepstakes’ prize winners.
  * **Other Features** : There may be other features available on our website which may require some personally identifiable information to use the feature. We only use the personally identifiable information to provide the feature and delete it within a reasonable period of time after the information is no longer necessary.

**Unsubscribing from Our Email List**

Every promotional e-mail you receive from CrystalGraphics should offer you the means to easily unsubscribe from CrystalGraphics’ mailing list within 72 hours. If you have difficulties using this feature, or want to report any problems with its effectiveness, you may report any such problems and/or request that you be immediately unsubscribed by [contacting us](mailto:%20abuse@CrystalGraphics.com). If you want to find out how and when you got on our mailing list, you may also contact us at this same email address.

**Aggregate Information**

Aggregate information about which pages visitors visit is only used for internal review as we continue to improve our website. 

**Our Commitment to Data Security**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate and effective physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect on-line.

**This Privacy Policy Is For Our On-line Customers and Website Visitors**

This Privacy Policy is for our customers and others who visit our website. It does not apply to information which we may collect by means other than over the Internet.

**Links**

Our policy is to occasionally provide electronic links to other sites which may be of interest to visitors to our website. However, content on websites can change quickly, so we cannot always guarantee the appropriateness of the content of sites we link to.

**How to Contact Us**

Should you have other questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please don't hesitate to contact us at:

Phone (408) 496-6175

CrystalGraphics, Inc.  
Marketing Department  
3350 Scott Blvd. Building 14  
Santa Clara, CA USA 95054

Your Friends at CrystalGraphics

Copyright © CrystalGraphics, Inc.

**Effective** : **_January 20, 2004_**
